let's consider the function f of x
equals e to the X and plot it on the
axis here we can draw the tangent line
to the curve which looks like the curve
locally and whose slope is the instant
rate of change of the Curve we can
compute the slope of this line and we
see that here it's .08 as we move the
point along the curve we see that the
slopes of the tangent lines get larger
in fact something even more interesting
happens in this example if we also plot
the y coordinate of the point we see
that as the point moves along the curve
the slope of the tangent line actually
equals the Y value
we can take this one step further where
we plot a new graph on a new set of axes
here the Y value will be the slope of
the tangent line from the first graph as
we move the point along the curve we map
out this graph the function f of x
equals e to the x is a special function
because its derivative or its slope
function f Prime of X is also e to the x